<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML -->
<!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 -->
<TaggedPDF-doc>
<?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?>
<?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:08:04        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2009-11-20T15:54:01</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>QuarkXPress(tm) 6.52</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-05-03T20:02:52+08:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-05-03T20:02:52+08:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>QuarkXPress(tm) 6.52</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
         <dc:title>
            <rdf:Alt>
               <rdf:li xml:lang="x-default">ALD8 House R099-113 #D0A617.qxd</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Alt>
         </dc:title>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdfx="http://ns.adobe.com/pdfx/1.3/">
         <pdfx:XPressPrivate>%%DocumentProcessColors: Black&#xA;%%DocumentCustomColors: (PANTONE 285 U)&#xA;%%CMYKCustomColor: .89 .43 0 0 (PANTONE 285 U)&#xA;%%EndComments</pdfx:XPressPrivate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:09eac3d3-ecc2-4e6d-943e-398e074fd166</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:aa1ef143-a2ea-4f02-99c0-1b99d2b0540f</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?>
<?xpacket end='r'?>

<Part>
<H2>The Oxford 3000™ d </H2>

<P>The keywords of the Oxford 3000 have been carefully selected by a group of language experts and experienced teachers as the words which should receive priority in vocabulary study because of their importance and usefulness. The selection is based on three criteria. </P>

<P>The words which occur most frequently in English are included, based on the information in the British National Corpus and the Oxford Corpus Collection. (A corpus is an electronically held collection of written or spoken texts, often consisting of hundreds of millions of words.) However, being frequent in the corpus alone is not enough for a word to qualify as a keyword: it may be that the word is used very frequently, but only in a narrowly defined area, such as newspapers or scientific articles. In order to avoid including these restricted words, we include as keywords only those words which are frequent across a range of different types of text. In other words, keywords are both frequent and used in a variety of contexts. In addition, the list includes some very important words which happen not to be used frequently, even though they are very familiar to most users of English. These include, for example, words for parts of the body, words used in travel, and words which are useful for explaining what you mean when you do not know the exact word for something. These words were identified by consulting a panel of over seventy experts in the fields of teaching and language study. </P>

<P>The words of the Oxford 3000 are shown in the main section of the dictionary in larger print, </P>

<P>and with a key symbol </P>

<P>d</P>

<Sect>
<P>immediately </P>
</Sect>

<P>derived from them, or are used in a variety of patterns. All of this means that each one of the keywords repays close study. </P>

<P>The list covers British and American English. It is arranged to emphasize the connections between words, so that words which are very closely related (including adverbs ending in -ly and opposites starting with un-) are grouped together. Some basic phrases are also included. Proper names (names of people, places, etc. beginning with a capital letter) and numbers are not included in the main list. </P>

<P>A separate list of words which are important for language study, but less important in everyday life, follows the main list. Knowing these words will help you to understand more of the information given in the entries, especially regarding the word’s grammar and register (whether it is formal, informal, etc.). </P>

<P>In order to make the definitions in this dictionary easy to understand, we have written them using the keywords of the Oxford 3000. All words used in normal definition text are keywords, or are on the list of language study terms. Numbers and proper names are also used in definitions. When it has been necessary to use a specialist term which is not in the Oxford 3000, the word is shown in small capitals, and in blue on the CD-ROM. If you do not know the meaning of this word, look it up in the dictionary: it will help you to understand the definition that you are interested in, and will probably be a useful word to learn because it will be related to the original word you looked up. </P>

<P>following. On the CD-ROM the keywords are shown in red. The most useful parts of the entries (particular parts of speech, meanings, phrasal verbs and idioms) are marked with a small key symbol. The entries for keywords often have extra information in the form of more examples of use, special notes explaining synonyms or related words, or helpful illustrations. This means that the keywords make an excellent starting point for expanding your vocabulary. With most keywords, there is far more to learn about them than the first meaning in the entry: often these words have many meanings, have a large family of words </P>

<P>The Oxford 3000 </P>

<Sect>
<P>a, an indefinite article </P>

<P>abandon v. abandoned adj.</P>
</Sect>

<P>d </P>

<Sect>
<P>ability n. able adj. </P>

<P>unable adj. </P>

<P>about adv., prep. </P>

<P>above prep., adv. </P>

<P>abroad adv. </P>

<P>absence n. </P>

<P>absent adj. </P>

<P>absolute adj. </P>

<P>absolutely adv. </P>

<P>absorb v. </P>

<P>abuse n., v. </P>

<P>academic adj. </P>

<P>accent n. </P>

<P>accept v. </P>

<P>acceptable adj. </P>

<P>unacceptable adj. </P>

<P>access n. </P>

<P>accident n. </P>

<P>by accident accidental adj. </P>

<P>accidentally adv. </P>

<P>accommodation n. </P>

<P>accompany v. </P>

<P>according to prep. </P>

<P>account n., v. </P>

<P>accurate adj. </P>

<P>accurately adv. </P>

<P>accuse v. </P>

<P>achieve v. </P>

<P>achievement n. </P>

<P>acid n. </P>

<P>acknowledge v. </P>

<P>acquire v. </P>

<P>across adv., prep. </P>

<P>act n., v. </P>

<P>action n. </P>

<P>take action active adj. </P>

<P>actively adv. </P>

<P>activity n. </P>

<P>actor, actress n. </P>

<P>actual adj. </P>

<P>actually adv. </P>

<P>ad iadvertisement </P>

<P>adapt v. </P>

<P>add v. </P>

<P>addition n. </P>

<P>in addition (to) </P>

<P>additional adj. </P>

<P>address n., v. </P>

<P>adequate adj. </P>

<P>adequately adv. </P>

<P>adjust v. </P>

<P>admiration n. </P>

<P>admire v. </P>

<P>admit v. </P>

<P>adopt v. </P>

<P>adult n., adj. </P>

<P>advance n., v. </P>

<P>advanced adj. in advance </P>

<P>advantage n. </P>

<P>take advantage of </P>

<P>adventure n. </P>

<P>advertise v. </P>

<P>advertising n. </P>

<P>advertisement </P>

<P>(also ad, advert) n. advice n. advise v. affair n. affect v. affection n. afford v. afraid adj. after prep., conj., adv. afternoon n. afterwards </P>

<P>(especially BrE)(NAmE </P>

<P>usually afterward) adv. again adv. against prep. age n. </P>

<P>aged adj. agency n. agent n. aggressive adj. ago adv. agree v. agreement n. ahead adv. aid n., v. aim n., v. air n. aircraft n. airport n. alarm n., v. </P>

<P>alarming adj. </P>

<P>alarmed adj. alcohol n. alcoholic adj., n. alive adj. all det., pron., adv. allow v. all right adj., adv., </P>

<P>exclamation ally n., v. </P>

<P>allied adj. almost adv. alone adj., adv. along prep., adv. alongside prep., adv. aloud adv. alphabet n. alphabetical adj. </P>

<P>alphabetically adv. already adv. also adv. alter v. alternative n., adj. </P>

<P>alternatively adv. although conj. altogether adv. always adv. </P>

<P>a.m. (NAmE also A.M.) abbr. </P>

<P>amaze v. amazing adj. amazed adj. </P>

<P>ambition n. ambulance n. among (also amongst) </P>

<P>prep. amount n., v. amuse v. </P>

<P>amusing adj. 
amused adj. 
</P>

<P>an ia, an analyse (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE analyze) v. analysis n. ancient adj. and conj. anger n. angle n. angry adj. </P>

<P>angrily adv. animal n. ankle n. anniversary n. announce v. annoy v. </P>

<P>annoying adj. annoyed adj. annual adj. </P>

<P>annually adv. another det., pron. answer n., v. anti-prefix anticipate v. anxiety n. anxious adj. </P>

<P>anxiously adv. any det., pron., adv. anyone </P>

<P>(also anybody) pron. anything pron. anyway adv. anywhere adv. apart adv. </P>

<P>apart from (also aside from especially in NAmE) prep. </P>

<P>apartment n. (especially NAmE) apologize (BrE also -ise) v. apparent adj. </P>

<P>apparently adv. appeal n., v. appear v. appearance n. apple n. application n. apply v. appoint v. appointment n. appreciate v. approach v., n. appropriate adj. approval n. approve (of) v. </P>

<P>approving adj. approximate adj. </P>

<P>approximately adv. April n. (abbr. Apr.) area n. argue v. argument n. arise v. arm n., v. </P>

<P>arms n. </P>

<P>armed adj. army n. around adv., prep. arrange v. arrangement n. </P>
</Sect>

<P>arrest v., n. arrival n. arrive v. arrow n. art n. article n. artificial adj. </P>

<P>artificially adv. artist n. artistic adj. as prep., adv., conj. ashamed adj. aside adv. </P>

<Sect>
<P>aside from </P>
</Sect>

<P>iapart from ask v. asleep adj. </P>

<P>fall asleep aspect n. assist v. assistance n. assistant n., adj. associate v. </P>

<P>associated with association n. assume v. assure v. at prep. atmosphere n. atom n. attach v. </P>

<P>attached adj. attack n., v. attempt n., v. </P>

<P>attempted adj. attend v. attention n. </P>

<P>pay attention attitude n. attorney n. </P>

<P>(especially NAmE) attract v. attraction n. attractive adj. audience n. August n. (abbr. Aug.) aunt n. author n. authority n. automatic adj. </P>

<P>automatically adv. autumn n. (especially BrE) available adj. average adj., n. avoid v. awake adj. award n., v. aware adj. away adv. awful adj. </P>

<P>awfully adv. awkward adj. awkwardly adv. </P>

<P>baby n. 
back n., adj., adv., v. 
background n. 
backwards (also backward 
</P>

<Sect>
<P>especially in NAmE) adv. backward adj. </P>
</Sect>

<P>bacteria n. 
</P>

<P>bad adj. 
go bad 
badly adv. 
</P>

<P>bad-tempered adj. 
bag n. 
baggage n. 
</P>

<P>(especially NAmE) 
bake v. 
balance n., v. 
ball n. 
ban v., n. 
band n. 
bandage n., v. 
bank n. 
bar n. 
bargain n. 
barrier n. 
base n., v. 
</P>

<P>based on 
basic adj. 
</P>

<P>basically adv. 
basis n. 
bath n. 
bathroom n. 
battery n. 
battle n. 
bay n. 
be v., auxiliary v. 
beach n. 
beak n. 
bear v. 
beard n. 
beat n., v. 
beautiful adj. 
</P>

<P>beautifully adv. 
beauty n. 
because conj. 
</P>

<P>because of prep. 
become v. 
bed n. 
bedroom n. 
beef n. 
beer n. 
before prep., conj., adv. 
begin v. 
</P>

<P>beginning n. 
</P>

<P>behalf n.: 
on behalf of sb, 
on sb’s behalf 
(BrE)(NAmE in behalf of 
sb, in sb’s behalf) 
</P>

<P>behave v. 
behaviour (BrE) 
</P>

<P>(NAmE behavior) n. 
behind prep., adv. 
belief n. 
believe v. 
bell n. 
belong v. 
below prep., adv. 
belt n. 
bend v., n. 
</P>

<P>bent adj. 
beneath prep., adv. 
benefit n., v. 
beside prep. 
bet v., n. 
</P>

<P>betting n. 
better, best igood, well 
between prep., adv. 
</P>

<P>beyond prep., adv. 
bicycle (also bike) n. 
bid v., n. 
big adj. 
bill n. 
bin n. (BrE) 
biology n. 
bird n. 
birth n. 
</P>

<P>give birth (to) 
birthday n. 
biscuit n. (BrE ) 
bit n. (especially BrE) 
</P>

<P>a bit 
bite v., n. 
bitter adj. 
</P>

<P>bitterly adv. 
black adj., n. 
blade n. 
blame v., n. 
blank adj., n. 
</P>

<P>blankly adv. 
blind adj. 
block n., v. 
blonde adj., n., 
</P>

<P>blond adj. 
blood n. 
blow v., n. 
blue adj., n. 
board n., v. 
</P>

<P>on board 
boat n. 
body n. 
boil v. 
bomb n., v. 
bone n. 
book n., v. 
boot n. 
border n. 
bore v. 
</P>

<Sect>
<P>boring adj. 
</P>
</Sect>

<P>bored adj. 
born: be born v. 
borrow v. 
boss n. 
both det., pron. 
bother v. 
bottle n. 
bottom n., adj. 
bound adj.: bound to 
bowl n. 
box n. 
boy n. 
boyfriend n. 
brain n. 
branch n. 
brand n. 
brave adj. 
bread n. 
break v., n. 
</P>

<P>broken adj. 
breakfast n. 
breast n. 
breath n. 
breathe v. 
</P>

<P>breathing n. 
breed v., n. 
brick n. 
bridge n. 
brief adj. 
</P>

<Sect>
<P>briefly adv. 
</P>
</Sect>

<P>bright adj. </P>

<P>brightly adv. brilliant adj. bring v. broad adj. </P>

<P>broadly adv. broadcast v., n. broken ibreak brother n. brown adj., n. brush n., v. bubble n. budget n. build v. </P>

<P>building n. bullet n. bunch n. burn v. </P>

<P>burnt adj. burst v. bury v. bus n. bush n. business n. businessman, </P>

<P>businesswoman n. busy adj. but conj. butter n. button n. buy v. buyer n. by prep., adv. bye exclamation </P>

<P>c abbr. icent cabinet n. cable n. cake n. calculate v. calculation n. call v., n. </P>

<P>be called calm adj., v., n. </P>

<P>calmly adv. camera n. camp n., v. </P>

<P>camping n. campaign n. can modal v., n. </P>

<P>cannot </P>

<P>could modal v. cancel v. cancer n. candidate n. candy n. (NAmE) cap n. capable (of) adj. capacity n. capital n., adj. captain n. capture v., n. car n. card n. cardboard n. care n., v. </P>

<P>take care (of) </P>

<P>care for career n. careful adj. </P>

<P>carefully adv. </P>

<P>careless adj. </P>

<P>carelessly adv. carpet n. </P>

<P>d </P>

<P>carrot n. carry v. case n. </P>

<P>in case (of) cash n. cast v., n. castle n. cat n. catch v. category n. cause n., v. CD n. cease v. ceiling n. celebrate v. celebration n. cell n. cellphone </P>

<P>(also cellular phone) n. </P>

<P>(especially NAmE) cent n. (abbr. c, ct) centimetre (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE centimeter) n. </P>

<P>(abbr. cm) central adj. centre (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE center) n. century n. ceremony n. certain adj., pron. </P>

<P>certainly adv. </P>

<P>uncertain adj. certificate n. chain n., v. chair n. chairman, </P>

<P>chairwoman n. challenge n., v. chamber n. chance n. change v., n. channel n. chapter n. character n. characteristic </P>

<P>adj., n. charge n., v. </P>

<P>in charge of charity n. chart n., v. chase v., n. chat v., n. cheap adj. </P>

<P>cheaply adv. cheat v., n. check v., n. cheek n. cheerful adj. </P>

<P>cheerfully adv. cheese n. chemical adj., n. chemist n. </P>

<P>chemist’s n. (BrE) chemistry n. cheque (BrE ) </P>

<P>(NAmE check) n. chest n. chew v. </P>

<Sect>
<P>chicken n. chief adj., n. child n.</P>
</Sect>

<P>d </P>

<P>The Oxford 3000 </P>

<Sect>
<P>chin n. chip n. chocolate n. choice n. choose v. chop v. church n. cigarette n. cinema n. </P>

<P>(especially BrE) circle n. circumstance n. citizen n. city n. civil adj. claim v., n. clap v., n. class n. classic adj., n. classroom n. clean adj., v. clear adj., v. </P>

<P>clearly adv. clerk n. clever adj. click v., n. client n. climate n. climb v. </P>

<P>climbing n. clock n. close /kl@Us, </P>

<P>NAmE kloUs/ adj. 
closely adv. 
</P>

<P>close /kl@Uz, NAmE kl@Uz/ v. closed adj. </P>

<P>closet n. </P>

<P>(especially NAmE) cloth n. clothes n. </P>

<P>clothing n. cloud n. club n. cm abbr. icentimetre coach n. coal n. coast n. coat n. code n. coffee n. coin n. cold adj., n. </P>

<P>coldly adv. collapse v., n. colleague n. collect v. collection n. college n. colour (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE color) n.,v. coloured (BrE) (NAmE colored) adj. </P>

<P>column n. combination n. combine v. come v. </P>

<P>comedy n. comfort n., v. comfortable adj. </P>

<P>comfortably adv. </P>

<P>uncomfortable adj. command v., n. comment n., v. commercial adj. commission n., v. commit v. commitment n. committee n. common adj. </P>

<P>in common </P>

<P>commonly adv. communicate v. communication n. community n. company n. compare v. comparison n. compete v. competition n. competitive adj. complain v. complaint n. complete adj., v. </P>

<P>completely adv. complex adj. complicate v. </P>

<P>complicated adj. computer n. concentrate v. concentration n. concept n. concern v., n. </P>

<P>concerned adj. </P>

<P>concerning prep. concert n. conclude v. conclusion n. concrete adj., n. condition n. conduct v., n. conference n. confidence n. confident adj. </P>

<P>confidently adv. confine v. </P>

<P>confined adj. confirm v. conflict n., v. confront v. confuse v. </P>

<P>confusing adj. </P>

<P>confused adj. confusion n. congratulations n. congress n. connect v. connection n. conscious adj. </P>

<P>unconscious adj. consequence n. conservative adj. consider v. considerable adj. </P>

<P>considerably adv. consideration n. consist of v. </P>

<P>constant adj. </P>

<P>constantly adv. construct v. construction n. consult v. consumer n. contact n., v. contain v. container n. contemporary adj. content n. contest n. context n. continent n. continue v. continuous adj. </P>

<P>continuously adv. contract n., v. contrast n., v. </P>

<P>contrasting adj. contribute v. contribution n. control n., v. </P>

<P>in control (of) </P>

<P>under control </P>

<P>controlled adj. </P>

<P>uncontrolled adj. convenient adj. convention n. conventional adj. conversation n. convert v. convince v. cook v., n. </P>

<P>cooking n. cooker n. (BrE) cookie n. </P>

<P>(especially NAmE) cool adj., v. cope (with) v. copy n., v. core n. corner n. correct adj., v. </P>

<P>correctly adv. cost n., v. cottage n. cotton n. cough v., n. </P>

<P>coughing n. could ican council n. count v. counter n. country n. countryside n. county n. couple n. </P>

<P>a couple courage n. course n. </P>

<P>of course court n. cousin n. cover v., n. </P>

<P>covered adj. </P>

<P>covering n. cow n. crack n., v. </P>

<P>cracked adj. </P>
</Sect>

<P>craft n. crash n., v. crazy adj. cream n., adj. create v. creature n. credit n. credit card n. crime n. criminal adj., n. crisis n. crisp adj. criterion n. critical adj. criticism n. criticize </P>

<P>(BrE also -ise) v. crop n. cross n., v. crowd n. </P>

<P>crowded adj. crown n. crucial adj. cruel adj. crush v. cry v., n. ct abbr. icent cultural adj. culture n. cup n. cupboard n. curb v. cure v., n. curious adj. </P>

<P>curiously adv. curl v., n. curly adj. current adj., n. </P>

<P>currently adv. curtain n. curve n., v. </P>

<P>curved adj. custom n. customer n. customs n. cut v., n. cycle n., v. </P>

<Sect>
<P>cycling n. </P>
</Sect>

<P>dad n. daily adj. damage n., v. damp adj. dance n., v. </P>

<P>dancing n. dancer n. danger n. dangerous adj. dare v. dark adj., n. data n. date n., v. daughter n. day n. dead adj. deaf adj. deal v., n. </P>

<P>deal with dear adj. death n. </P>

<P>debate n., v. debt n. decade n. decay n., v. December n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Dec.) decide v. decision n. declare v. decline n., v. decorate v. decoration n. decorative adj. decrease v., n. deep adj., adv. </P>

<P>deeply adv. defeat v., n. defence (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE defense) n. defend v. define v. definite adj. </P>

<P>definitely adv. definition n. degree n. delay n., v. deliberate adj. </P>

<P>deliberately adv. delicate adj. delight n., v. </P>

<P>delighted adj. deliver v. delivery n. demand n., v. demonstrate v. dentist n. deny v. department n. departure n. depend (on) v. deposit n., v. depress v. </P>

<P>depressing adj. </P>

<P>depressed adj. depth n. derive v. describe v. description n. desert n., v. </P>

<P>deserted adj. deserve v. design n., v. desire n., v. desk n. desperate adj. </P>

<P>desperately adv. despite prep. destroy v. destruction n. detail n. </P>

<P>in detail </P>

<P>detailed adj. determination n. determine v. </P>

<P>determined adj. develop v. development n. device n. devote v. </P>

<P>devoted adj. </P>

<P>diagram n. diamond n. diary n. dictionary n. die v. </P>

<P>dying adj. diet n. difference n. different adj. </P>

<P>differently adv. difficult adj. difficulty n. dig v. dinner n. direct adj., v. </P>

<P>directly adv. direction n. director n. dirt n. dirty adj. disabled adj. disadvantage n. disagree v. disagreement n. disappear v. disappoint v. </P>

<Sect>
<P>disappointing adj. </P>
</Sect>

<P>disappointed adj. disappointment n. disapproval n. disapprove (of) v. </P>

<P>disapproving adj. disaster n. disc </P>

<Sect>
<P>(also disk, especially </P>
</Sect>

<P>in NAmE) n. discipline n. discount n. discover v. discovery n. discuss v. discussion n. disease n. disgust v., n. </P>

<Sect>
<P>disgusting adj. </P>
</Sect>

<P>disgusted adj. dish n. dishonest adj. </P>

<P>dishonestly adv. disk n. dislike v., n. dismiss v. display v., n. dissolve v. distance n. distinguish v. distribute v. distribution n. district n. disturb v. </P>

<P>disturbing adj. divide v. division n. divorce n., v. </P>

<P>divorced adj. do v., auxiliary v. </P>

<P>undo v. doctor n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Dr, NAmE Dr.) document n. </P>

<P>dog n. 
dollar n. 
domestic adj. 
dominate v. 
door n. 
dot n. 
double adj.,det.,adv., 
</P>

<P>n.,v. doubt n., v. down adv., prep. downstairs adv., adj., n. downwards </P>

<P>(also downward especially in NAmE) adv. downward adj. </P>

<P>dozen n., det. </P>

<P>Dr (BrE) (also Dr. NAmE, BrE) abbr. idoctor </P>

<P>draft n., adj., v. drag v. drama n. dramatic adj. </P>

<P>dramatically adv. draw v. </P>

<P>drawing n. drawer n. dream n., v. dress n., v. </P>

<P>dressed adj. drink n., v. drive v., n. </P>

<P>driving n. driver n. drop v., n. drug n. drugstore n. (NAmE ) drum n. drunk adj. dry adj., v. due adj. </P>

<P>due to dull adj. dump v., n. during prep. dust n., v. duty n. DVD n. </P>

<P>each det., pron. each other </P>

<P>(also one another) pron. ear n. early adj., adv. earn v. earth n. ease n., v. east n., adj., adv. eastern adj. easy adj. </P>

<P>easily adv. eat v. economic adj. economy n. edge n. edition n. editor n. educate v. </P>

<P>educated adj. education n. </P>

<P>effect n. effective adj. </P>

<P>effectively adv. </P>

<P>d </P>

<P>efficient adj. </P>

<P>efficiently adv. effort n. </P>

<P>e.g. abbr. 
egg n. 
either det., pron., adv. 
elbow n. 
elderly adj. 
elect v. 
election n. 
electric adj. 
electrical adj. 
electricity n. 
electronic adj. 
elegant adj. 
element n. 
elevator n. (NAmE ) 
else adv. 
elsewhere adv. 
email (also e-mail) n., v. 
embarrass v. 
</P>

<P>embarrassing adj. </P>

<P>embarrassed adj. embarrassment n. emerge v. emergency n. emotion n. emotional adj. </P>

<P>emotionally adv. emphasis n. emphasize </P>

<P>(BrE also -ise) v. empire n. employ v. </P>

<P>unemployed adj. employee n. employer n. employment n. </P>

<P>unemployment n. empty adj., v. enable v. encounter v., n. encourage v. encouragement n. end n., v. </P>

<P>in the end </P>

<P>ending n. enemy n. energy n. engage v. </P>

<P>engaged adj. engine n. engineer n. </P>

<P>engineering n. enjoy v. enjoyable adj. enjoyment n. enormous adj. enough det., pron., adv. enquiry (also inquiry </P>

<P>especially in NAmE) n. ensure v. enter v. entertain v. </P>

<P>entertaining adj. entertainer n. entertainment n. </P>

<P>The Oxford 3000 </P>

<Sect>
<P>enthusiasm n. enthusiastic adj. entire adj.</P>
</Sect>

<P>d </P>

<Sect>
<P>entirely adv. entitle v. entrance n. entry n. envelope n. environment n. environmental adj. equal adj., n., v. </P>

<P>equally adv. equipment n. equivalent adj., n. error n. escape v., n. especially adv. essay n. essential adj., n. </P>
</Sect>

<P>essentially adv. establish v. estate n. estimate n., v. etc. (full form et cetera) euro n. even adv., adj. evening n. event n. eventually adv. ever adv. every det. everyone (also everybody) </P>

<Sect>
<P>pron. everything pron. everywhere adv. evidence n. evil adj., n. ex- prefix exact adj. </P>

<P>exactly adv. exaggerate v. </P>

<P>exaggerated adj. exam n. examination n. examine v. example n. excellent adj. except prep., conj. exception n. exchange v., n. </P>

<P>in exchange (for) </P>

<P>excite v. exciting adj. excited adj. </P>

<P>excitement n. exclude v. </P>

<P>excluding prep. excuse n., v. executive n., adj. exercise n., v. exhibit v., n. exhibition n. exist v. existence n. exit n. expand v. expect v. </P>

<P>expected adj. unexpected adj. unexpectedly adv. </P>

<P>expectation n. expense n. expensive adj. experience n., v. </P>

<P>experienced adj. experiment n., v. expert n., adj. explain v. explanation n. explode v. explore v. explosion n. export v., n. expose v. express v., adj. expression n. extend v. extension n. extensive adj. extent n. extra adj., n., adv. extraordinary </P>

<P>adj. extreme adj., n. </P>

<P>extremely adv. eye n. </P>

<P>face n., v. facility n. fact n. factor n. factory n. fail v. failure n. faint adj. </P>

<P>faintly adv. fair adj. </P>

<P>fairly adv. </P>

<P>unfair adj. </P>

<P>unfairly adv. faith n. faithful adj. </P>

<P>faithfully adv. </P>

<P>Yours faithfully (BrE) fall v., n. </P>

<P>fall over false adj. fame n. familiar adj. family n., adj. famous adj. fan n. fancy v., adj. far adv., adj. </P>

<P>further adj. farm n. </P>

<P>farming n. farmer n. farther, farthest ifar fashion n. fashionable adj. fast adj., adv. fasten v. fat adj., n. father n. faucet n. (NAmE) fault n. favour (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE favor) n. </P>

<P>in favour/favor (of) favourite (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE favorite) adj., n. fear n., v. feather n. feature n., v. February n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Feb.) federal adj. fee n. feed v. feel v. </P>

<P>feeling n. fellow n., adj. female adj., n. fence n. festival n. fetch v. fever n. few det., adj., pron. </P>

<P>a few field n. fight v., n. </P>

<P>fighting n. figure n., v. file n. fill v. film n., v. final adj., n. </P>

<P>finally adv. finance n., v. financial adj. find v. </P>

<P>find out sth fine adj. </P>

<P>finely adv. finger n. finish v., n. </P>

<P>finished adj. fire n., v. set fire to firm n., adj., adv. firmly adv. first det., ordinal number, adv., n. </P>

<P>at first fish n., v. </P>

<P>fishing n. fit v., adj. fix v. </P>

<P>fixed adj. flag n. flame n. flash v., n. flat adj., n. flavour (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE flavor) n.,v. flesh n. flight n. float v. flood n., v. floor n. flour n. flow n., v. flower n. flu n. fly v., n. </P>

<P>flying adj., n. focus v., n. fold v., n. </P>

<P>folding adj. </P>

<P>follow v. </P>

<P>following adj., n., prep. food n. foot n. football n. for prep. force n., v. forecast n., v. foreign adj. forest n. forever </P>

<P>(BrE also for ever) adv. forget v. forgive v. fork n. form n., v. formal adj. </P>

<P>formally adv. former adj. </P>

<P>formerly adv. formula n. fortune n. forward </P>

<P>(also forwards) adv. </P>

<P>forward adj. found v. foundation n. frame n., v. free adj., v., adv. </P>

<P>freely adv. freedom n. freeze v. </P>

<P>frozen adj. frequent adj. frequently adv. fresh adj. </P>

<P>freshly adv. Friday n. (abbr. Fri.) fridge n. (BrE) friend n. </P>

<P>make friends (with) friendly adj. </P>

<P>unfriendly adj. friendship n. frighten v. </P>

<P>frightening adj. </P>

<P>frightened adj. from prep. front n., adj. </P>

<P>in front (of) frozen ifreeze fruit n. fry v., n. fuel n. full adj. </P>

<P>fully adv. fun n., adj. </P>

<P>make fun of function n., v. fund n., v. fundamental adj. funeral n. funny adj. fur n. furniture n. further, furthest ifar future n., adj. </P>
</Sect>

<P>g abbr. igram gain v., n. gallon n. gamble v., n. </P>

<P>gambling n. game n. gap n. garage n. garbage n. </P>

<P>(especially NAmE) garden n. gas n. gasoline n. (NAmE) gate n. gather v. gear n. general adj. </P>

<P>generally adv. </P>

<P>in general generate v. generation n. generous adj. </P>

<P>generously adv. gentle adj. </P>

<P>gently adv. gentleman n. genuine adj. </P>

<P>genuinely adv. geography n. get v. </P>

<P>get on </P>

<P>get off giant n., adj. gift n. girl n. girlfriend n. give v. </P>

<P>give sth away 
give sth out 
give sth up 
</P>

<P>glad adj. glass n. </P>

<P>glasses n. global adj. glove n. glue n., v. gm abbr. igram go v. </P>

<P>go down 
go up 
be going to 
</P>

<P>goal n. god n. gold n., adj. good adj.,n. </P>

<P>good at good for goodbye </P>

<P>exclamation, n. goods n. govern v. government n. governor n. grab v. grade n., v. gradual adj. </P>

<P>gradually adv. grain n. gram (BrE also gramme) n. </P>

<P>(abbr. g, gm) </P>

<P>grammar n. 
grand adj. 
grandchild n. 
granddaughter n. 
grandfather n. 
grandmother n. 
grandparent n. 
grandson n. 
grant v., n. 
grass n. 
grateful adj. 
grave n., adj. 
gray (NAmE) igrey 
great adj. 
</P>

<P>greatly adv. green adj., n. grey (BrE)(NAmE usually </P>

<Sect>
<P>gray) adj., n. </P>
</Sect>

<P>grocery (especially BrE) (NAmE usually grocery store) n. groceries n. </P>

<P>ground n. group n. grow v. </P>

<P>grow up growth n. guarantee n., v. guard n., v. guess v., n. guest n. guide n., v. guilty adj. gun n. guy n. </P>

<P>habit n. hair n. hairdresser n. half n., det., </P>

<P>pron., adv. hall n. hammer n. hand n., v. handle v., n. hang v. happen v. happiness n. </P>

<Sect>
<P>unhappiness n. </P>
</Sect>

<P>happy adj. happily adv. unhappy adj. </P>

<P>hard adj., adv. 
hardly adv. 
harm n., v. 
harmful adj. 
harmless adj. 
hat n. 
hate v., n. 
hatred n. 
have v., auxiliary v. 
</P>

<P>have to modal v. he pron. head n., v. headache n. heal v. health n. healthy adj. hear v. </P>

<Sect>
<P>hearing n. </P>
</Sect>

<P>heart n. heat n., v. </P>

<P>heating n. heaven n. heavy adj. </P>

<P>heavily adv. heel n. height n. hell n. hello exclamation, n. help v., n. helpful adj. hence adv. her pron., det. </P>

<P>hers pron. here adv. hero n. herself pron. hesitate v. hi exclamation hide v. high adj., adv. </P>

<P>highly adv. highlight v., n. highway n. </P>

<P>(especially NAmE ) hill n. him pron. himself pron. hip n. hire v., n. his det., pron. historical adj. history n. hit v., n. hobby n. hold v., n. hole n. holiday n. hollow adj. holy adj. home n., adv. homework n. honest adj. </P>

<P>honestly adv. </P>

<P>honour (BrE) (NAmE honor) n. in honour/honor of </P>

<P>hook n. hope v., n. horizontal adj. horn n. horror n. horse n. hospital n. host n., v. hot adj. hotel n. hour n. house n. </P>

<P>housing n. household n., adj. how adv. however adv. huge adj. human adj., n. humorous adj. humour (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE humor) n. hungry adj. </P>

<P>hunt v. </P>

<P>hunting n. hurry v.,n. </P>

<P>d </P>

<P>in a hurry hurt v. husband n. </P>

<P>I pron. ice n. ice cream n. idea n. ideal adj., n. </P>

<P>ideally adv. identify v. identity n. </P>

<P>i.e. abbr. 
if conj. 
ignore v. 
ill adj. (especiallyBrE) 
illegal adj. 
</P>

<P>illegally adv. illness n. illustrate v. image n. imaginary adj. imagination n. imagine v. immediate adj. </P>

<P>immediately adv. immoral adj. impact n. impatient adj. </P>

<P>impatiently adv. implication n. imply v. import n., v. importance n. important adj. </P>

<P>importantly adv. </P>

<P>unimportant adj. impose v. impossible adj. impress v. </P>

<P>impressed adj. impression n. impressive adj. improve v. improvement n. in prep., adv. inability n. inch n. incident n. include v. </P>

<P>including prep. income n. increase v., n. </P>

<P>increasingly adv. indeed adv. independence n. independent adj. </P>

<P>independently adv. index n. indicate v. indication n. indirect adj. </P>

<P>indirectly adv. individual adj., n. indoors adv. </P>

<P>indoor adj. industrial adj. </P>

<Sect>
<P>industry n. inevitable adj. </P>

<P>inevitably adv. </P>
</Sect>

<P>d </P>

<P>The Oxford 3000 </P>

<Sect>
<P>infect v. </P>

<P>infected adj. infection n. infectious adj. influence n., v. inform v. informal adj. information n. ingredient n. initial adj., n. </P>

<P>initially adv. initiative n. injure v. </P>

<P>injured adj. injury n. ink n. inner adj. innocent adj. inquiry ienquiry insect n. insert v. inside prep., adv., </P>

<P>n., adj. insist (on) v. install v. instance n. </P>

<P>for instance instead adv. </P>

<P>instead of institute n. institution n. instruction n. instrument n. insult v., n. </P>

<P>insulting adj. insurance n. intelligence n. intelligent adj. intend v. </P>

<P>intended adj. intention n. interest n., v. </P>

<P>interesting adj. </P>

<P>interested adj. interior n., adj. internal adj. international adj. Internet n. interpret v. interpretation n. interrupt v. interruption n. interval n. interview n., v. into prep. introduce v. introduction n. invent v. invention n. invest v. investigate v. investigation n. investment n. invitation n. invite v. involve v. </P>

<P>involved in involvement n. iron n., v. irritate v. </P>

<P>irritating adj. </P>

<P>irritated adj. -ish suffix island n. issue n., v. it pron.,det. </P>

<P>its det. item n. itself pron. </P>

<P>jacket n. jam n. January n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Jan.) jealous adj. jeans n. jelly n. jewellery (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE jewelry) n. job n. join v. joint adj., n. </P>

<P>jointly adv. joke n., v. journalist n. journey n. joy n. judge n., v. judgement </P>

<P>(also judgment </P>

<P>especially in NAmE) n. juice n. July n. (abbr. Jul.) jump v., n. June n. (abbr. Jun.) junior adj., n. just adv. justice n. justify v. </P>

<P>justified adj. </P>

<P>k abbr. ikilometre keen adj. </P>

<P>keen on keep v. key n., adj. keyboard n. kick v., n. kid n. kill v. </P>

<P>killing n. </P>

<P>kilogram (BrE also kilogramme) (also kilo) n. (abbr. kg) </P>

<P>kilometre (BrE) (NAmE kilometer) n. (abbr. k, km) </P>

<P>kind n., adj. kindly adv. unkind adj. </P>

<P>kindness n. 
king n. 
kiss v., n. 
kitchen n. 
km abbr. ikilometre 
knee n. 
knife n. 
</P>

<P>knit v. knitted adj. knitting n. </P>

<P>knock v., n. knot n. know v. </P>

<P>unknown adj. well known adj. knowledge n. </P>

<P>l abbr. ilitre label n., v. laboratory, lab n. labour (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE labor) n. lack n., v. </P>

<P>lacking adj. lady n. lake n. lamp n. land n., v. landscape n. lane n. language n. large adj. </P>

<P>largely adv. last det., adv., n., v. late adj., adv. </P>

<P>later adv., adj. </P>

<P>latest adj., n. latter adj., n. laugh v., n. launch v., n. law n. lawyer n. lay v. layer n. lazy adj. lead /li;d/ v., n. </P>

<P>leading adj. leader n. leaf n. league n. lean v. learn v. least det.,pron., adv. </P>

<P>at least leather n. leave v. </P>

<P>leave out lecture n. left adj., adv., n. leg n. legal adj. </P>

<P>legally adv. lemon n. lend v. length n. less det., pron., adv. lesson n. let v. letter n. level n., adj. library n. licence (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE license) n. license v. lid n. lie v., n. life n. </P>
</Sect>

<P>lift v., n. light n., adj., v. lightly adv. like prep.,v.,conj. unlike prep.,adj. likely adj., adv. unlikely adj. limit n., v. </P>

<P>limited adj. line n. link n., v. lip n. liquid n., adj. list n., v. listen (to) v. literature n. litre (BrE)(NAmE liter) n. </P>

<Sect>
<P>(abbr. l) </P>
</Sect>

<P>little adj., det., pron., adv. a little det., pron. </P>

<P>live /laIv/ adj., adv. live /lIv/ v. </P>

<P>living adj. lively adj. load n., v. </P>

<P>unload v. loan n. local adj. </P>

<P>locally adv. locate v. </P>

<P>located adj. location n. lock v., n. logic n. logical adj. lonely adj. long adj., adv. look v.,n. </P>

<Sect>
<P>look after 
(especially BrE) 
look at 
look for 
look forward to 
</P>
</Sect>

<P>loose adj. </P>

<P>loosely adv. lord n. lorry n. (BrE ) lose v. </P>

<P>lost adj. loss n. lot: a lot (of) </P>

<P>(also lots (of)) pron., det., adv. loud adj., adv. </P>

<P>loudly adv. love n., v. lovely adj. lover n. low adj., adv. loyal adj. luck n. lucky adj. </P>

<P>unlucky adj. luggage n. </P>

<P>(especially BrE) lump n. lunch n. lung n. </P>

<P>machine n. machinery n. mad adj. magazine n. magic n., adj. mail n., v. main adj. </P>

<P>mainly adv. maintain v. major adj. majority n. make v., n. </P>

<P>make sth up make-up n. male adj., n. mall n. </P>

<P>(especially NAmE) man n. manage v. management n. manager n. manner n. manufacture v., n. </P>

<P>manufacturing n. manufacturer n. many det., pron. map n. March n. (abbr. Mar.) march v., n. mark n., v. market n. </P>

<P>marketing n. marriage n. marry v. </P>

<P>married adj. mass n., adj. massive adj. master n. match n., v. </P>

<P>matching adj. mate n., v. material n., adj. mathematics </P>

<P>(also maths BrE, </P>

<P>math NAmE) n. matter n., v. maximum adj., n. may modal v. May n. maybe adv. mayor n. me pron. meal n. mean v. </P>

<P>meaning n. means n. </P>

<P>by means of meanwhile adv. measure v., n. measurement n. meat n. media n. medical adj. medicine n. medium adj., n. meet v. </P>

<P>meeting n. melt v. member n. membership n. </P>

<P>memory n. in memory of mental adj. </P>

<P>mentally adv. mention v. menu n. mere adj. </P>

<P>merely adv. mess n. message n. metal n. method n. metre (BrE ) </P>

<P>(NAmE meter) n. mg abbr. imilligram mid-combining form midday n. middle n., adj. midnight n. might modal v. mild adj. mile n. military adj. milk n. milligram </P>

<Sect>
<P>(BrE also milligramme) </P>

<P>n. (abbr. mg) </P>
</Sect>

<P>millimetre (BrE ) (NAmE millimeter) n. (abbr. mm) </P>

<P>mind n., v. mine pron., n. mineral n., adj. minimum adj., n. minister n. ministry n. minor adj. minority n. minute n. mirror n. miss v., n. </P>

<P>Miss n. missing adj. mistake n., v. mistaken adj. mix v., n. </P>

<P>mixed adj. mixture n. mm abbr. imillimetre mobile adj. mobile phone </P>

<P>(also mobile) n. (BrE) model n. modern adj. mom (NAmE) imum moment n. Monday n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Mon.) money n. monitor n., v. month n. mood n. moon n. moral adj. </P>

<P>morally adv. more det., pron., adv. moreover adv. morning n. most det., pron., adv. mostly adv. </P>

<P>mother n. motion n. motor n. motorcycle </P>

<P>(BrE also motorbike) n. mount v., n. mountain n. mouse n. mouth n. move v., n. </P>

<P>moving adj. movement n. movie n. </P>

<P>(especially NAmE) movie theater n. (NAmE ) Mr (BrE) </P>

<P>(also Mr. NAmE, BrE) 
abbr. 
</P>

<P>Mrs (BrE) (also Mrs. NAmE, BrE) abbr. </P>

<P>Ms (BrE) (also Ms. NAmE, BrE) abbr. </P>

<P>much det., pron., adv. 
mud n. 
multiply v. 
mum (BrE) 
</P>

<P>(NAmE mom) n. 
murder n., v. 
muscle n. 
museum n. 
music n. 
musical adj. 
musician n. 
must modal v. 
my det. 
myself pron. 
mysterious adj. 
mystery n. 
</P>

<P>nail n. 
naked adj. 
name n., v. 
narrow adj. 
nation n. 
national adj. 
natural adj. 
</P>

<P>naturally adv. 
nature n. 
navy n. 
near adj., adv., prep. 
nearby adj., adv. 
nearly adv. 
neat adj. 
</P>

<P>neatly adv. 
</P>

<P>necessary adj. 
necessarily adv. 
unnecessary adj. 
</P>

<P>neck n. 
need v., modal v., n. 
needle n. 
negative adj. 
neighbour (BrE )(NAmE 
</P>

<P>neighbor) n. 
neighbourhood (BrE ) 
</P>

<P>(NAmE neighborhood) n. 
neither det., pron., adv. 
nephew n. 
nerve n. 
</P>

<P>nervous adj. nervously adv. nest n., v. </P>

<P>d </P>

<P>net n. network n. never adv. nevertheless adv. new adj. newly adv. news n. newspaper n. next adj., adv., n. </P>

<P>next to prep. nice adj. </P>

<P>nicely adv. niece n. night n. no exclamation, det. No. (also no.) abbr. </P>

<P>inumber nobody (also no one) </P>

<P>pron. noise n. noisy adj. </P>

<P>noisily adv. non-prefix none pron. nonsense n. no one inobody nor conj., adv. normal adj., n. </P>

<P>normally adv. north n., adj., adv. northern adj. nose n. not adv. note n., v. nothing pron. notice n., v. </P>

<P>take notice of noticeable adj. novel n. November n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Nov.) now adv. nowhere adv. nuclear adj. number </P>

<P>(abbr. No., no.) n. nurse n. nut n. </P>

<P>obey v. object n., v. objective n., adj. observation n. observe v. obtain v. obvious adj. </P>

<P>obviously adv. occasion n. occasionally adv. occupy v. </P>

<P>occupied adj. occur v. ocean n. o’clock adv. October n. (abbr. Oct.) odd adj. </P>

<P>oddly adv. </P>

<P>The Oxford 3000 </P>

<Sect>
<P>of prep. off adv., prep. offence (BrE)</P>
</Sect>

<P>d </P>

<Sect>
<P>(NAmE offense) n. offend v. offensive adj. offer v., n. office n. officer n. official adj., n. </P>

<P>officially adv. often adv. oh exclamation oil n. OK (also okay) </P>
</Sect>

<P>exclamation, adj., adv. old adj. old-fashioned adj. on prep., adv. once adv., conj. one number, det., pron. one another ieach other onion n. only adj., adv. onto prep. open adj., v. </P>

<Sect>
<P>openly adv. </P>

<P>opening n. operate v. operation n. opinion n. opponent n. opportunity n. oppose v. </P>

<P>opposing adj. opposed to opposite adj., adv., </P>

<P>n., prep. opposition n. option n. or conj. orange n., adj. order n., v. </P>

<P>in order to ordinary adj. organ n. organization </P>

<P>(BrE also -isation) n. </P>

<P>organize (BrE also -ise) v. organized adj. </P>

<P>origin n. original adj., n. </P>

<P>originally adv. other adj., pron. otherwise adv. ought to modal v. our det. </P>

<P>ours pron. ourselves pron. out (of) adv., prep. outdoors adv. </P>
</Sect>

<P>outdoor adj. outer adj. outline v., n. output n. outside n., adj., prep., adv. outstanding adj. oven n. over adv., prep. </P>

<Sect>
<P>overall adj., adv. 
overcome v. 
owe v. 
own adj., pron., v. 
owner n. 
</P>

<P>p abbr. ipage, penny 
pace n. 
pack v., n. 
package n., v. 
</P>

<P>packaging n. 
packet n. 
page n. (abbr. p) 
pain n. 
painful adj. 
paint n., v. 
</P>

<P>painting n. 
painter n. 
pair n. 
palace n. 
pale adj. 
pan n. 
panel n. 
pants n. 
paper n. 
parallel adj. 
parent n. 
park n., v. 
parliament n. 
part n. 
</P>

<P>take part (in) 
particular adj. 
</P>

<P>particularly adv. 
partly adv. 
partner n. 
partnership n. 
party n. 
pass v. 
</P>

<P>passing n., adj. 
passage n. 
passenger n. 
passport n. 
past adj., n., prep., adv. 
path n. 
patience n. 
patient n., adj. 
pattern n. 
pause v., n. 
pay v., n. 
payment n. 
peace n. 
peaceful adj. 
peak n. 
pen n. 
pence n. ipenny 
pencil n. 
penny n. (abbr. p) 
pension n. 
people n. 
pepper n. 
per prep. 
per cent (NAmE usually 
</P>

<P>percent) n., adj., adv. perfect adj. </P>

<P>perfectly adv. perform v. performance n. performer n. perhaps adv. period n. </P>

<P>permanent adj. </P>

<P>permanently adv. permission n. permit v. person n. personal adj. </P>

<P>personally adv. personality n. persuade v. pet n. petrol n. (BrE ) phase n. philosophy n. phone itelephone photocopy n., v. photograph n., v. </P>

<P>(also photo n.) photographer n. photography n. phrase n. physical adj. </P>

<P>physically adv. physics n. piano n. pick v. </P>

<P>pick sth up picture n. piece n. pig n. pile n., v. pill n. pilot n. pin n., v. pink adj., n. pint n. (abbr. pt) pipe n. pitch n. pity n. place n., v. </P>

<P>take place plain adj. plan n., v. </P>

<P>planning n. plane n. planet n. plant n., v. plastic n., adj. plate n. platform n. play v., n. player n. pleasant adj. </P>

<P>pleasantly adv. 
unpleasant adj. 
</P>

<P>please exclamation, v. pleasing adj. pleased adj. </P>

<P>pleasure n. plenty pron., adv., </P>

<P>n., det. plot n., v. plug n. plus prep., n., adj., conj. </P>

<P>p.m. (NAmE also P.M.) </P>

<P>abbr. pocket n. poem n. poetry n. point n., v. </P>

<P>pointed adj. </P>

<P>poison n., v. poisonous adj. pole n. police n. policy n. polish n., v. polite adj. </P>

<P>politely adv. political adj. </P>

<P>politically adv. politician n. politics n. pollution n. pool n. poor adj. pop n., v. popular adj. population n. port n. pose v., n. position n. positive adj. possess v. possession n. possibility n. possible adj. </P>

<P>possibly adv. post n., v. post office n. pot n. potato n. potential adj., n. </P>

<P>potentially adv. pound n. pour v. powder n. power n. powerful adj. practical adj. </P>

<P>practically adv. practice n. </P>

<P>(BrE, NAmE), </P>

<P>v. (NAmE) practise v. (BrE) praise n., v. prayer n. precise adj. </P>

<P>precisely adv. predict v. prefer v. preference n. pregnant adj. premises n. preparation n. prepare v. </P>

<P>prepared adj. presence n. present adj., n., v. presentation n. preserve v. president n. press n., v. pressure n. presumably adv. pretend v. pretty adv., adj. prevent v. previous adj. </P>

<P>previously adv. price n. </P>
</Sect>

<Table>
<TR>
<TD>pride n. </TD>

<TD>punch v., n. </TD>

<TD>receipt n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>priest n. </TD>

<TD>punish v. </TD>

<TD>receive v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>primary adj. </TD>

<TD>punishment n. </TD>

<TD>recent adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>primarily adv. </TD>

<TD>pupil n. (especially BrE) </TD>

<TD>recently adv. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>prime minister n. </TD>

<TD>purchase n., v. </TD>

<TD>reception n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>prince n. </TD>

<TD>pure adj. </TD>

<TD>reckon v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>princess n. </TD>

<TD>purely adv. </TD>

<TD>recognition n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>principle n. </TD>

<TD>purple adj., n. </TD>

<TD>recognize </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>print v., n. </TD>

<TD>purpose n. </TD>

<TD>(BrE also -ise) v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>printing n. </TD>

<TD>on purpose </TD>

<TD>recommend v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>printer n. </TD>

<TD>pursue v. </TD>

<TD>record n., v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>prior adj. </TD>

<TD>push v., n. </TD>

<TD>recording n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>priority n. </TD>

<TD>put v. </TD>

<TD>recover v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>prison n. </TD>

<TD>put sth on </TD>

<TD>red adj., n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>prisoner n. </TD>

<TD>put sth out </TD>

<TD>reduce v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>private adj. </TD>

<TD/>

<TD>reduction n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>privately adv. </TD>

<TD>qualification n. </TD>

<TD>refer to v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>prize n. </TD>

<TD>qualify v. </TD>

<TD>reference n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>probable adj. </TD>

<TD>qualified adj. </TD>

<TD>reflect v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>probably adv. </TD>

<TD>quality n. </TD>

<TD>reform v., n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>problem n. </TD>

<TD>quantity n. </TD>

<TD>refrigerator n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>procedure n. </TD>

<TD>quarter n. </TD>

<TD>refusal n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>proceed v. </TD>

<TD>queen n. </TD>

<TD>refuse v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>process n., v. </TD>

<TD>question n., v. </TD>

<TD>regard v., n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>produce v. </TD>

<TD>quick adj. </TD>

<TD>regarding prep. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>producer n. </TD>

<TD>quickly adv. </TD>

<TD>region n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>product n. </TD>

<TD>quiet adj. </TD>

<TD>regional adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>production n. </TD>

<TD>quietly adv. </TD>

<TD>register v., n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>profession n. </TD>

<TD>quit v. </TD>

<TD>regret v., n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>professional adj., n. </TD>

<TD>quite adv. </TD>

<TD>regular adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>professor n. </TD>

<TD>quote v. </TD>

<TD>regularly adv. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>profit n. </TD>

<TD/>

<TD>regulation n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>program n., v. </TD>

<TD>race n., v. </TD>

<TD>reject v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>programme n. (BrE) </TD>

<TD>racing n. </TD>

<TD>relate v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>progress n., v. </TD>

<TD>radio n. </TD>

<TD>related (to) adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>project n., v. </TD>

<TD>rail n. </TD>

<TD>relation n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>promise v., n. </TD>

<TD>railway (BrE ) </TD>

<TD>relationship n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>promote v. </TD>

<TD>(NAmE railroad) n. </TD>

<TD>relative adj., n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>promotion n. </TD>

<TD>rain n., v. </TD>

<TD>relatively adv. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>prompt adj., v. </TD>

<TD>raise v. </TD>

<TD>relax v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>promptly adv. </TD>

<TD>range n. </TD>

<TD>relaxed adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>pronounce v. </TD>

<TD>rank n., v. </TD>

<TD>relaxing adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>pronunciation n. </TD>

<TD>rapid adj. </TD>

<TD>release v., n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>proof n. </TD>

<TD>rapidly adv. </TD>

<TD>relevant adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>proper adj. </TD>

<TD>rare adj. </TD>

<TD>relief n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>properly adv. </TD>

<TD>rarely adv. </TD>

<TD>religion n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>property n. </TD>

<TD>rate n., v. </TD>

<TD>religious adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>proportion n. </TD>

<TD>rather adv. </TD>

<TD>rely on v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>proposal n. </TD>

<TD>rather than </TD>

<TD>remain v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>propose v. </TD>

<TD>raw adj. </TD>

<TD>remaining adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>prospect n. </TD>

<TD>re- prefix </TD>

<TD>remains n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>protect v. </TD>

<TD>reach v. </TD>

<TD>remark n., v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>protection n. </TD>

<TD>react v. </TD>

<TD>remarkable adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>protest n., v. </TD>

<TD>reaction n. </TD>

<TD>remarkably adv. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>proud adj. </TD>

<TD>read v. </TD>

<TD>remember v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>proudly adv. </TD>

<TD>reading n. </TD>

<TD>remind v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>prove v. </TD>

<TD>reader n. </TD>

<TD>remote adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>provide v. </TD>

<TD>ready adj. </TD>

<TD>removal n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>provided </TD>

<TD>real adj. </TD>

<TD>remove v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>(also providing) conj. </TD>

<TD>really adv. </TD>

<TD>rent n., v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>pt abbr. ipint </TD>

<TD>realistic adj. </TD>

<TD>rented adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>pub n. </TD>

<TD>reality n. </TD>

<TD>repair v., n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>public adj., n. </TD>

<TD>realize (BrE also -ise) v. </TD>

<TD>repeat v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>in public </TD>

<TD>really ireal </TD>

<TD>repeated adj. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>publicly adv. </TD>

<TD>rear n., adj. </TD>

<TD>repeatedly adv. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>publication n. </TD>

<TD>reason n. </TD>

<TD>replace v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>publicity n. </TD>

<TD>reasonable adj. </TD>

<TD>reply n., v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>publish v. </TD>

<TD>reasonably adv. </TD>

<TD>report v., n. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>publishing n. </TD>

<TD>unreasonable adj. </TD>

<TD>represent v. </TD>
</TR>

<TR>
<TD>pull v., n. </TD>

<TD>recall v. </TD>

<TD>representative n., adj. </TD>
</TR>
</Table>

<P>reproduce v. 
reputation n. 
request n., v. d 
require v. 
requirement n. 
rescue v., n. 
research n. 
reservation n. 
reserve v., n. 
resident n., adj. 
resist v. 
resistance n. 
resolve v. 
resort n. 
resource n. 
respect n., v. 
respond v. 
response n. 
responsibility n. 
responsible adj. 
rest n.,v. 
</P>

<P>the rest 
restaurant n. 
restore v. 
restrict v. 
</P>

<P>restricted adj. 
restriction n. 
result n., v. 
retain v. 
retire v. 
</P>

<P>retired adj. 
retirement n. 
return v., n. 
reveal v. 
reverse v., n. 
review n., v. 
revise v. 
revision n. 
revolution n. 
reward n., v. 
rhythm n. 
rice n. 
rich adj. 
rid v.: get rid of 
ride v., n. 
</P>

<P>riding n. 
rider n. 
ridiculous adj. 
right adj., adv., n. 
</P>

<P>rightly adv. 
ring n., v. 
rise n., v. 
risk n., v. 
rival n., adj. 
river n. 
road n. 
rob v. 
rock n. 
role n. 
roll n., v. 
romantic adj. 
roof n. 
room n. 
root n. 
rope n. 
rough adj. 
</P>

<P>roughly adv. 
</P>

<P>round adj., adv., prep., n. rounded adj. </P>

<Sect>
<P>route n. routine n., adj. </P>
</Sect>

<P>The Oxford 3000 </P>

<Sect>
<P>row /r@U, NAmE roU/ n.</P>
</Sect>

<P>d </P>

<Sect>
<P>royal adj. rub v. rubber n. rubbish n. </P>

<P>(especially BrE) </P>

<P>rude adj. rudely adv. </P>

<P>ruin v., n. </P>

<P>ruined adj. </P>

<P>rule n., v. </P>

<P>ruler n. </P>

<P>rumour n. </P>

<P>run v., n. </P>

<P>running n. </P>

<P>runner n. </P>

<P>rural adj. </P>

<P>rush v., n. </P>

<P>sack n., v. sad adj. </P>

<P>sadly adv. </P>

<P>sadness n. </P>

<P>safe adj. </P>

<P>safely adv. </P>

<P>safety n. </P>

<P>sail v., n. </P>

<P>sailing n. </P>

<P>sailor n. </P>

<P>salad n. </P>

<P>salary n. </P>

<P>sale n. </P>

<P>salt n. </P>

<P>salty adj. </P>

<P>same adj., pron. </P>

<P>sample n. </P>

<P>sand n. </P>

<P>satisfaction n. </P>

<P>satisfy v. </P>

<P>satisfied adj. satisfying adj. </P>

<P>Saturday n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Sat.) </P>

<P>sauce n. </P>

<P>save v. </P>

<P>saving n. </P>

<P>say v. </P>

<P>scale n. </P>

<P>scare v., n. </P>

<P>scared adj. </P>

<P>scene n. </P>

<P>schedule n., v. </P>

<P>scheme n. </P>

<P>school n. </P>

<P>science n. </P>

<P>scientific adj. </P>

<P>scientist n. </P>

<P>scissors n. </P>

<P>score n., v. </P>

<P>scratch v., n. </P>

<P>scream v., n. </P>

<P>screen n. </P>

<P>screw n., v. </P>

<P>sea n. </P>

<P>seal n., v. </P>

<P>search n., v. </P>

<P>season n. </P>

<P>seat n. </P>

<P>second det., ordinal number, adv., n. </P>

<P>secondary adj. secret adj., n. </P>

<P>secretly adv. secretary n. section n. sector n. secure adj., v. security n. see v. seed n. seek v. seem linking v. select v. selection n. self n. </P>

<P>self-combining form sell v. senate n. senator n. send v. senior adj., n. sense n. sensible adj. sensitive adj. sentence n. separate adj., v. </P>

<P>separated adj. </P>

<P>separately adv. separation n. September n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Sept.) series n. serious adj. </P>

<P>seriously adv. servant n. serve v. service n. session n. set n., v. settle v. several det., pron. severe adj. </P>

<P>severely adv. sew v. </P>

<P>sewing n. sex n. sexual adj. </P>

<P>sexually adv. shade n. shadow n. shake v., n. shall modal v. shallow adj. shame n. shape n., v. </P>

<P>shaped adj. share v., n. sharp adj. </P>

<P>sharply adv. shave v. she pron. sheep n. sheet n. shelf n. shell n. shelter n., v. shift v., n. </P>

<P>shine v. shiny adj. ship n. shirt n. shock n., v. </P>

<P>shocking adj. </P>

<P>shocked adj. shoe n. shoot v. </P>

<P>shooting n. shop n., v. </P>

<P>shopping n. short adj. shortly adv. shot n. should modal v. shoulder n. shout v., n. show v., n. shower n. shut v., adj. shy adj. sick adj. </P>

<P>be sick (BrE) </P>

<P>feel sick (especially BrE) side n. sideways adj., adv. sight n. sign n., v. signal n., v. signature n. significant adj. </P>

<P>significantly adv. silence n. silent adj. silk n. silly adj. silver n., adj. similar adj. </P>

<P>similarly adv. simple adj. </P>

<P>simply adv. since prep., conj., adv. sincere adj. </P>

<P>sincerely adv. Yours sincerely (BrE) sing v. </P>

<P>singing n. singer n. single adj. sink v. sir n. sister n. sit v. </P>

<P>sit down site n. situation n. size n. </P>

<P>-sized </P>

<P>skilful (BrE) (NAmE skillful) adj. skilfully (BrE) (NAmE skillfully) adv. </P>

<P>skill n. </P>

<P>skilled adj. skin n. skirt n. sky n. sleep v., n. sleeve n. </P>
</Sect>

<P>slice n., v. slide v. slight adj. </P>

<P>slightly adv. slip v. slope n., v. slow adj. </P>

<P>slowly adv. small adj. smart adj. smash v., n. smell v., n. smile v., n. smoke n., v. </P>

<P>smoking n. smooth adj. </P>

<P>smoothly adv. snake n. snow n., v. so adv., conj. </P>

<P>so that soap n. social adj. </P>

<P>socially adv. society n. sock n. soft adj. </P>

<P>softly adv. software n. soil n. soldier n. solid adj., n. solution n. solve v. some det., pron. somebody </P>

<P>(also someone) pron. somehow adv. something pron. sometimes adv. somewhat adv. somewhere adv. son n. song n. soon adv. </P>

<P>as soon as sore adj. sorry adj. sort n., v. soul n. sound n., v. soup n. sour adj. source n. south n.,adj.,adv. southern adj. space n. spare adj., n. speak v. </P>

<P>spoken adj. speaker n. special adj. </P>

<P>specially adv. specialist n. specific adj. </P>

<P>specifically adv. speech n. speed n. spell v., n. </P>

<Sect>
<P>spelling n. </P>
</Sect>

<P>spend v. 
spice n. 
spicy adj. 
spider n. 
spin v. 
spirit n. 
spiritual adj. 
spite n.: in spite of 
split v., n. 
spoil v. 
spoken ispeak 
spoon n. 
sport n. 
spot n. 
spray n., v. 
spread v. 
spring n. 
square adj., n. 
squeeze v., n. 
stable adj., n. 
staff n. 
stage n. 
stair n. 
stamp n., v. 
stand v., n. 
</P>

<P>stand up 
standard n., adj. 
star n., v. 
stare v., n. 
start v., n. 
state n., adj., v. 
statement n. 
station n. 
statue n. 
status n. 
stay v., n. 
steady adj. 
</P>

<P>steadily adv. 
</P>

<P>unsteady adj. 
steal v. 
steam n. 
steel n. 
steep adj. 
</P>

<P>steeply adv. 
steer v. 
step n., v. 
stick v.,n. 
</P>

<P>stick out 
sticky adj. 
stiff adj. 
</P>

<P>stiffly adv. 
still adv., adj. 
sting v., n. 
stir v. 
stock n. 
stomach n. 
stone n. 
stop v., n. 
store n., v. 
storm n. 
story n. 
stove n. 
straight adv., adj. 
strain n. 
strange adj. 
</P>

<P>strangely adv. 
stranger n. 
strategy n. 
stream n. 
street n. 
</P>

<P>strength n. stress n., v. </P>

<P>stressed adj. stretch v. strict adj. </P>

<P>strictly adv. strike v., n. </P>

<P>striking adj. string n. strip v., n. stripe n. </P>

<P>striped adj. stroke n., v. strong adj. </P>

<P>strongly adv. structure n. struggle v., n. student n. studio n. study n., v. stuff n. stupid adj. style n. subject n. substance n. substantial adj. </P>

<P>substantially adv. substitute n., v. succeed v. success n. successful adj. </P>

<P>successfully adv. unsuccessful adj. such det., pron. </P>

<P>such as suck v. sudden adj. </P>

<P>suddenly adv. suffer v. suffering n. sufficient adj. </P>

<P>sufficiently adv. sugar n. suggest v. suggestion n. suit n., v. </P>

<P>suited adj. suitable adj. suitcase n. sum n. summary n. summer n. sun n. Sunday n. (abbr. Sun.) superior adj. supermarket n. supply n., v. support n., v. supporter n. suppose v. sure adj., adv. </P>

<Sect>
<P>make sure </P>
</Sect>

<P>surely adv. surface n. surname n. </P>

<Sect>
<P>(especially BrE) </P>
</Sect>

<P>surprise n., v. surprising adj. surprisingly adv. surprised adj. </P>

<P>surround v. surrounding adj. surroundings n. </P>

<P>survey n., v. survive v. suspect v., n. suspicion n. suspicious adj. swallow v. swear v. </P>

<P>swearing n. sweat n., v. sweater n. sweep v. sweet adj., n. swell v. </P>

<P>swelling n. swollen adj. swim v. </P>

<P>swimming n. swimming pool n. swing n., v. switch n.,v. </P>

<P>switch sth off </P>

<P>switch sth on swollen iswell symbol n. sympathetic adj. sympathy n. system n. </P>

<P>table n. tablet n. tackle v., n. tail n. take v. </P>

<P>take sth off </P>

<P>take (sth) over talk v., n. tall adj. tank n. tap v., n. tape n. target n. task n. taste n., v. tax n., v. taxi n. tea n. teach v. </P>

<P>teaching n. teacher n. team n. tear /te@(r), </P>

<P>NAmE ter/ v.,n. tear /tI@(r), </P>

<P>NAmE tIr/ n. technical adj. technique n. technology n. telephone (also phone) </P>

<P>n., v. television (also TV) n. tell v. temperature n. temporary adj. </P>

<P>temporarily adv. tend v. tendency n. tension n. </P>

<P>tent n. term n. terrible adj. </P>

<P>d </P>

<P>terribly adv. test n., v. text n. than prep., conj. thank v. </P>

<P>thanks exclamation, n. 
thank you 
</P>

<P>exclamation, n. that det., pron., conj. the definite article theatre (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE theater) n. their det. </P>

<P>theirs pron. them pron. theme n. themselves pron. then adv. theory n. there adv. therefore adv. they pron. thick adj. </P>

<P>thickly adv. thickness n. thief n. thin adj. thing n. think v. </P>

<P>thinking n. thirsty adj. this det., pron. thorough adj. </P>

<P>thoroughly adv. though conj., adv. thought n. thread n. threat n. threaten v. </P>

<P>threatening adj. throat n. through prep., adv. throughout prep., adv. throw v. </P>

<P>throw sth away thumb n. Thursday n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Thur., Thurs.) thus adv. ticket n. tidy adj., v. </P>

<P>untidy adj. tie v., n. tie sth up tight adj.,adv. </P>

<P>tightly adv. till iuntil time n. timetable n. </P>

<P>(especially BrE) tin n. tiny adj. tip n., v. tire v. (BrE,NAmE),n. </P>

<P>(NAmE)(BrE tyre) 
tiring adj. 
tired adj. 
</P>

<P>title n. 
to prep.,infinitive marker 
today adv., n. 
</P>

<P>d </P>

<P>The Oxford 3000 </P>

<Sect>
<P>toe n. 
together adv. 
toilet n. 
tomato n. 
tomorrow adv., n. 
ton n. 
tone n. 
tongue n. 
tonight adv., n. 
tonne n. 
too adv. 
tool n. 
tooth n. 
top n., adj. 
topic n. 
total adj., n. 
</P>

<P>totally adv. touch v., n. tough adj. tour n., v. tourist n. towards </P>
</Sect>

<P>(also toward especially in </P>

<Sect>
<P>NAmE) prep. towel n. tower n. town n. toy n., adj. trace v., n. track n. trade n., v. </P>

<P>trading n. tradition n. traditional adj. </P>

<P>traditionally adv. traffic n. train n., v. </P>

<P>training n. transfer v., n. transform v. translate v. translation n. transparent adj. transport(BrE) </P>
</Sect>

<P>(NAmE transportation)  n. </P>

<Sect>
<P>transport v. (BrE, NAmE) trap n., v. travel v., n. traveller (BrE) </P>

<P>(NAmE traveler) n. treat v. treatment n. tree n. trend n. trial n. triangle n. trick n., v. trip n., v. tropical adj. trouble n. trousers n. </P>

<P>(especially BrE ) truck n. (especially NAmE) </P>

<P>true adj. truly adv. Yours Truly (NAmE) trust n., v. truth n. try v. tube n. Tuesday n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Tue., Tues.) tune n., v. tunnel n. turn v., n. TV itelevision twice adv. twin n., adj. twist v., n. </P>

<P>twisted adj. type n., v. typical adj. </P>

<P>typically adv. tyre n. (BrE) (NAmE tire) </P>

<P>ugly adj. ultimate adj. </P>

<P>ultimately adv. umbrella n. unable iable unacceptable </P>

<P>iacceptable uncertain icertain uncle n. uncomfortable </P>

<P>icomfortable unconscious iconscious uncontrolled </P>

<P>icontrol under prep., adv. underground adj., adv. underneath </P>

<P>prep., adv. understand v. </P>

<P>understanding n. underwater adj., adv. underwear n. undo ido unemployed </P>

<P>iemploy unemployment iemployment unexpected, unexpectedly iexpect unfair, unfairly ifair unfortunate adj. </P>

<P>unfortunately adv. unfriendly ifriendly unhappiness </P>

<P>ihappiness unhappy ihappy uniform n., adj. unimportant </P>

<P>iimportant union n. unique adj. unit n. unite v. </P>

<P>united adj. universe n. university n. unkind ikind unknown iknow unless conj. unlike ilike unlikely ilikely unload iload unlucky ilucky unnecessary </P>

<P>inecessary unpleasant </P>

<P>ipleasant unreasonable </P>

<P>ireasonable unsteady isteady unsuccessful </P>

<P>isuccessful untidy itidy until (also till) conj., prep. unusual, unusually </P>

<P>iusual unwilling, unwillingly i </P>

<P>willing up adv., prep. upon prep. upper adj. upset v., adj. </P>

<P>upsetting adj. upside down adv. upstairs adv.,adj., n. upwards </P>

<P>(also upward especially in 
NAmE) adv. 
upward adj. 
</P>

<P>urban adj. urge v., n. urgent adj. us pron. use v.,n. </P>

<P>used adj. </P>

<P>used to sth/to </P>

<P>doing sth </P>

<P>used to modal v. useful adj. useless adj. user n. usual adj. </P>

<P>usually adv. </P>

<P>unusual adj. </P>

<P>unusually adv. </P>

<P>vacation n. valid adj. valley n. valuable adj. value n., v. van n. variation n. variety n. various adj. vary v. </P>

<P>varied adj. vast adj. vegetable n. vehicle n. venture n., v. version n. vertical adj. very adv. via prep. victim n. victory n. video n. </P>
</Sect>

<P>view n., v. village n. violence n. violent adj. </P>

<P>violently adv. virtually adv. virus n. visible adj. vision n. visit v., n. visitor n. vital adj. vocabulary n. voice n. volume n. vote n., v. </P>

<P>wage n. 
waist n. 
wait v. 
waiter, waitress n. 
wake (up) v. 
walk v., n. 
</P>

<P>walking n. wall n. wallet n. wander v., n. want v. war n. warm adj., v. warmth n. warn v. </P>

<P>warning n. wash v. </P>

<P>washing n. waste v., n., adj. watch v., n. water n. wave n., v. way n. we pron. weak adj. weakness n. wealth n. weapon n. wear v. weather n. web n. </P>

<P>the Web n. website n. wedding n. Wednesday n. </P>

<P>(abbr. Wed., Weds.) week n. weekend n. weekly adj. weigh v. weight n. welcome v., adj., n., </P>

<P>exclamation well adv., adj., exclamation </P>

<P>as well (as) well known iknow west n.,adj.,adv. western adj. wet adj. what pron.,det. whatever det.,pron. wheel n. </P>

<P>when adv., pron., conj. will modal v., n. wonder v. writer n. whenever conj. willing adj. wonderful adj. wrong adj., adv. where adv., conj. willingly adv. wood n. go wrong </P>

<P>d </P>

<P>whereas conj. unwilling adj. wooden adj. wrongly adv. 
wherever conj. unwillingly adv. wool n. 
whether conj. willingness n. word n. yard n. 
which pron., det. win v. work v., n. yawn v., n. 
while conj.,n. winning adj. working adj. yeah exclamation 
whilst conj. wind /waInd/ v. worker n. year n. 
</P>

<P>(especiallyBrE) wind sth up world n. yellow adj., n. 
whisper v., n. wind /wInd/ n. worry v., n. yes exclamation, n. 
whistle n., v. window n. worrying adj. yesterday adv., n. 
white adj., n. wine n. worried adj. yet adv., conj. 
who pron. wing n. worse, worst ibad you pron. 
whoever pron. winner n. worship n., v. young adj. 
whole adj., n. winter n. worth adj. your det. 
whom pron. wire n. would modal v. yours pron. 
whose det., pron. wise adj. wound n., v. yourself pron. 
why adv. wish v., n. wounded adj. youth n. 
wide adj. with prep. wrap v. 
</P>

<P>widely adv. withdraw v. wrapping n. zero number 
width n. within prep. wrist n. zone n. 
wife n. without prep. write v. 
wild adj. witness n., v. writing n. 
</P>

<P>wildly adv. woman n. written adj. 
</P>

<Sect>
<H4>Language study terms </H4>

<P>Knowing these 80 words will be useful in your study of English and will also help you to use the Oxford Advanced Learner’s Dictionary more effectively. It includes words to do with grammar, pronunciation and punctuation. </P>

<P>abbreviation n. idiom n. question mark n. 
active adj., n. imperative adj., n. question tag 
adjective n. indirect speech (also tag question) n. 
adverb n. ireported speech quotation marks 
apostrophe n. infinitive n. (BrE also inverted commas) n. 
article n. inverted commas reflexive adj. 
auxiliary (also auxiliary verb) n. iquotation marks register n. 
bracket n. ironic adj. regular adj. 
clause n. irregular adj. relative adj. 
colon n. literal adj. reported speech 
comma n. literary adj. (also indirect speech) n. 
comparative adj., n. modal n. saying n. 
compound n., adj. noun n. semicolon n. 
conditional adj., n. object n. simple adj. 
conjunction n. ordinal n. singular n., adj. 
consonant n. paragraph n. slang n. 
contraction n. parenthesis n. slash n. 
countable adj. part of speech subject n. 
continuous (also word class) n. suffix n. 
</P>

<P>iprogressive participle n. superlative adj., n. 
derivative n. particle n. syllable n. 
determiner n. passive adj., n. taboo adj. 
dialect n. perfect adj. tag question 
entry n. period n. (NAmE) iquestion tag 
exclamation n. phrasal verb n. tense n. 
exclamation mark plural n., adj. uncountable adj. 
</P>

<P>(especially BrE)(NAmE usually possessive adj., n. verb n. </P>

<P>exclamation point) n. prefix n. vowel n. figurative adj. preposition n. word class full stop n. (BrE) progressive (also continuous) adj. ipart of speech gerund n. pronoun n. hyphen n. punctuation n. </P>
</Sect>
</Part>
</TaggedPDF-doc>
